<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remembering Om Johari</title>
    <description>Memorial site for Om Johari (1940-2015)
</description>
    <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://remember-omjohari.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 21:39:34 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 21:39:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Michael Tracy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Om – My Thank You for accepting me as a AARP instructor in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel your encouragement and mentoring over the years with AARP  gave me the confidence to be a AARP instructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You had always an open view about my ideas and it was a pleasure to work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were a kind man and seeing the accomplishments you achieve over  your lifetime, you can add great job for your community service with AARP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, your son wrote a great tribute to you and  should be very proud of what he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michael Tracy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 17:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-michael-tracy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-michael-tracy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Margarita Patmore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Om… I met you just seven weeks ago… and yet… you left footprints in my heart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your teachings, your spirit and your beautiful soul have become an eternal flame within me that will guide and inspire my journey forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all you shared with me, for showing me how much beauty there is in meditation, in the simplicity of things, and in being selfless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for allowing me to see your courage in letting go when your moment came.  Thank you for reminding me how temporary life is and the importance of living it to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You taught me to meditate in so many ways… to accept others without judgement, and to honor myself, embracing all that it means to be me!  Your body is gone but your spirit resides in me forever… I love you and always will.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 17:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-margarita-patmore.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-margarita-patmore.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Janet Street</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My first memory of him was as instructor of the AARP Driver Safety class that I attended in 2012.  He was thorough and help me to adjust the side mirrors on my car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I saw him at the Arlington Heights Senior Center where he was having one of his meditations.  After that I started receiving them by email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 16:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-janet-street.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-janet-street.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Pauline Reeves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have known Dr. Johari  for about twenty five years.  I am so sad to read of his passing.
He was an amazing man to say the least. I feel privileged to have spoken many times with him.
He will be missed by many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Dr. Johari for having touched my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 16:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-pauline-reeves.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-pauline-reeves.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Ed and Ann Niewiadomski</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My husband and I had the pleasure of attending his AARP Driving school..and in doing so..became attached to your dad..
magically to his words…..
I got his newsletters..and so appreciated his views on life..feelings and all..
Please accept our deepest sympathy…Great loss…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 15:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-ann-niewiadomski.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-ann-niewiadomski.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Kalyan Chakravarti</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Om was my class mate in IIT Kharagpur. He visited my house in Pune, where he had a friend, Dr Trivedi, who live close to me. He was a person of multiple talents. He excelled in his studies, and to the best of my knowledge, is to date, the only Metallurgical Engineer who won the president’s gold medal of IIT Kharagpur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in life, he turned his attention to spirituality, and the ancient alternative medical system of Ayurveda, widely practised in India. He did a lot of research on the beneficial effects of coconut in the prevention and arrest of Alzheimer’s disease. He was passionate about community service and philanthropy. We, IIT Alumni grieve his loss, and pray for his Atma in a higher liberated form in his next life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kalyan Chakravarti, IIT KGP, Class of 1963&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 15:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-kalyan-chakravarti.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-kalyan-chakravarti.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Elizabeth Barry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks you so much for taking the time to write everyone and for the details of Om’s life and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so moved reading what you wrote us. He will be missed but I will remember him always. HE knows right now, that I play better Sudoku, drive more consciously, laugh more and sleep better because of him.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he taught me best of all, that all things are as they are supposed to be and to not stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again and I am so very sorry for your loss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-elizabeth-barry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-elizabeth-barry.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Jessica Pollitt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Om Johari will be sorely missed at the Fox Lake District Library by staff and patrons alike.  He frequently taught both meditation and AARP Driver Safety classes here. He was always an upbeat and kind person that everyone wanted to be around and I personally really enjoyed the opportunity to work with him and to get to know him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jessica Pollitt, Head of Adult Services, Fox Lake District Library&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-jessica-pollitt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-jessica-pollitt.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Lucy Francis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During a meditation class at the Palatine Library,  Dr. Johari talked about death.  He explained that  in death “I am not here.” &lt;br /&gt;
That one short sentence has helped me deal with the loss of many loved ones.  The time comes when we are all not here. Life will go on as it is meant to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 12:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-lucy-francis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-lucy-francis.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Bobbi Fields</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended the visitation and service for Om yesterday. It was beautiful. For those who don’t know, he died from a cancer that they found out about last November or so. He didn’t want chemo treatments and then several days ago had surgery, went home and had a heart attack. Of course he was not afraid of dying and he told his son to go to sleep while he was dying. Doesn’t that sound just like him? The last thing he said to us at last week’s class was to look at your loved ones with deep gratitude that they are in your life. There are few people that have had such a deep effect as he did. He taught us how to destress ourselves. What a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Om Johari was one of the few stable forces in my life for many years. He studied all of the great minds of the world and then imparted his best gleaned wisdom to us. I got the feeling that his constant studying and serving the community was also his way of living a full and satisfying life. Like in the bible, he taught us all to “fish” for ourselves, by gaining the ability to meditate and step outside of our stress and problems.  We were truly blessed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 12:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-bobbi-fields.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://remember-omjohari.github.io/remembrances/2015/03/26/from-bobbi-fields.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>remembrances</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
